Welcome back, this is Dr. Salik, and this is inside Practice Activity number three.
Before we get started with the practice activity, I wanted to talk about a
process that will not going to practice in the class,
but it's something you need to be aware of.
If you look at the simulated data sets
that have been provided for you, you'll see that
they're fairly pristine
and clean data.
There is a value in every column and
in every cell.
When you collect data, that's not always the way it works out.
There's usually missing values of values that are incorrect,
and you have to reconcile
us with a process called data cleaning before you begin your analysis.
Data cleaning is the process of preparing data for analysis
by removing or modifying data that is incorrect
incomplete, irrelevant, duplicated, or improperly
formatted. There is a variety of ways and variety of techniques for doing this.
generally speaking,
that's an important step before you begin
doing your data analysis. There are a variety of ways you can add on your data in analysis.
end up with incomplete or corrupt data in your data set. One example might be
somebody starts to take your survey, they lose their internet connection,
come back at a later time and complete it.
Now you have two rows of data
for the same individual, and one of those rows is an incomplete set of
values.
In the data cleaning process, you might make a decision to
eliminate that set of values.
Data cleaning is an art and
a science in itself, so in this course, in the simulated data sets I've provided,
provided, I have already taken care of that step, and the data you'll be using
is clean and pristine.
In this practice exercise, you're going
going to analyze numerical data that comes from a Likert scale type
survey, you're going to review the descriptive statistics for each of the
variables you analyze, and then you're going to identify the mean
and identify the standard deviation. And finally, you'll count